Jack Hughes

Ambitious learner with experience developing data pipelines using Python, SQL, and AWS. My inquisitive attitude and background providing technical support equips me with the technical and soft skills needed to succeed as an independent, resourceful data engineer.

Oldham, Greater Manchester **07307 051 546**

jack apps@outlook.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/jackprofile https://hughesydev.github.io

EXPERIENCE

Generation, remote — *Jr. Data Engineer programme*

SEPT 2020 - NOV 2020

- Received professional mentoring on modern software construction practices covering testing, Git, Agile, and Continuous Delivery (DevOps, CI/CD, IaC) principles
- Applied these best practices in individual and group projects creating robust, secure data solutions

Out of work — Recovering from injury

JUNE 2019 - APR 2020

Littlefish, Rochdale — Service Desk Engineer

APRIL 2019 - JUNE 2019

 Responsible for tier 1, 2, & 3 technical support and general management of IT infrastructure for hundreds of businesses.

Sodexo, Salford— Support Technician

JANUARY 2020 - MARCH 2020

 Duties included in-house technical support (tiers 1 & 2), and maintaining thousands of assets (tills, scanners, cash registers etc.) ensuring speedy uptime across stores.

Arcadis, Manchester — Service Desk Analyst

MAY 2015 - JULY 2018

- Provided technical support in a fast-paced environment, regularly beating performance KPIs.
- Mentored new colleagues on tools and processes

EDUCATION

The Oldham College

SEPT 2012 - MAY 2014

- BTEC Diploma Uniformed Public Services (DDD Grade)
- GCSE Maths
- GCSE English

SKILLS / TOOLS

Experience with and exposure to the below:

Python - data cleaning - AWS S3
SQL - Linux - AWS Lambda
Agile - Bash - AWS Redshift
Git - Docker - CloudFormation

PROJECTS

Infinite-Data System (group project)

A cloud-native serverless ETL pipeline on AWS. Developed in a 7-person team using Agile methodology.

The project architecture had AWS S3 as the data source and implemented three interconnected AWS Lambda services to ingest the data, transform it to fit our database schema, then load the transformed data into an AWS Redshift data warehouse. We then ran queries against the data warehouse to generate visualisations.

The development process used GitHub Actions for CI/CD and AWS CloudFormation to provision/deploy the infrastructue and application code.

This solution allowed stakeholders to easily monitor daily sales data, enabling better data-driven decision-making and advancing their ability to meet and adapt to customer needs.

SpaceBar (individual project)

https://github.com/HughesyDev/SpaceBar

A terminal-based Python & MySQL app designed to emulate a drink/round-ordering service. Facilitates secure creating, reading, updating, and deleting from the database. Applied professional software construction practices using Docker & virtual environments to ensure a clean and reproducible development environment and managed source-control with Git.